Hello everyone and welcome
to English Pot, my name is Marco.
Hi everyone, my name is Catherine and today
we have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right, today we
are dealing with a house
that is filled with
different types of bugs.
Ew, bugs. Well, it's
summertime, so it's not that
uncommon, but not a
pleasant thing to deal with.
That's right, so we're
going to call an exterminator,
so you might be asking
yourself what that is,
but before we explain, why don't you
listen to the dialogue for the first time?
Hi, did you call for an exterminator?
Yes, thank goodness you're here.
These bugs are driving us crazy.
What sort of pests are we dealing with?
We just bought this house and it is
infected with just about everything.
We have termites in the
wood, cockroaches all over the
place, and last night I saw a
huge rat out in the backyard.
Well, there's nothing
that we can handle.
I'll spray the floorboards and
walls to get rid of the cockroaches,
but the termites will
be harder to get rid of.
We will have to cover the
entire house and fumigated.
Unfortunately, that
means you will have to
find a place to stay
for the next three days.
No problem, just get rid of the bugs.
All right, we're back, so now we have six
key words that we've chosen now for you.
Let's take a look at those
now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, Marco, you've
already told our users a
very first word that
would be exterminator.
What is an exterminator?
It's a person, right?
That's right, it's a person
that has the job to exterminate
or to delete or eliminate
different types of bugs or pests.
So an exterminator's job is to kill bugs.
That's right.
And usually an exterminator comes to
your home or your office to do this, right?
That's right, so maybe in your house
you have a lot of different types of bugs.
Maybe you have, I don't know, spiders.
So an exterminator will come and
he will try to get rid of the spiders.
Great, so an exterminator
in a general sense
gets rid of pests and
pests as our next word.
That's right, a pest.
Now we're talking about bugs and
they can be considered a sort of pest.
Well, pest though is a
more general term, right?
So you can say pest about
something like rats or mice.
That's right, so basically
some type of animal that is
very annoying and also causes
some sort of harm or danger.
Right, so there's a movie if I
remember correctly in the 1990s.
It was terrible and it was called the pest.
Yeah, that's right.
And it's all about this
person who is very annoying.
So you can even say an annoying
person or a bothersome person is a pest.
That's right, you're such a pest.
Okay, so obviously our
home is filled with bugs and
that's what the person
said that it is infested.
Okay, so a place like an
office building or like you said,
Marco, a home is infested
if it is filled with something.
And so infested means it's
filled with something bad.
That's right, so in this case
the house is infested with bugs.
They're living upstairs,
downstairs in the
basement in the kitchen,
they're everywhere.
That's right, and she said that we, well
actually they have termites in the wood.
Alright, so termites are a special kind of
bug that almost always live in wood, right?
That's right, the little bugs
that I think eat the wood.
And this is why they're so
dangerous because they make the
house weak because they eat
all the wood that supports it.
So you can say the house fell down
because it was infested with termites.
That's right, termites.
And also we have a very common
pest or a bug, we have cockroaches.
I hate these and they're
everywhere this summer.
Cockroaches come in
different sizes, some are big,
some are small, but they're
very, very strong bugs.
They can live through anything.
That's right, they're
small, usually brown, but
sometimes I think you
can't see black cockroaches.
That's right, and they love to be near
food and decaying things like garbage bins.
That's right, so a very
common type of pest cockroach.
And in order to get rid of
termites and cockroaches and
all these types of bugs, we
have to fumigate the house.
Okay, so this is one method that
the exterminator uses to kill bugs.
And like in the dialogue, when
you fumigate a house, basically
you fill the house with
fumes or gases that kill bugs.
So people, like you and me, we can't
be in the house when that happens, right?
That's right.
Actually, if you see an
exterminator, he will always fumigate
wearing a mask, so he doesn't
inhale those poisonous gas.
Right, so it's very dangerous
for people, and you have
to make sure you talk to
your exterminator to make sure
that the gases he's using
aren't getting into your body.
That's right.
Okay, so why don't we listen to the
dialogue again, and we'll be back in a bit.
Hi, did you call for an exterminator?
Yes! Thank goodness you're here.
These bugs are driving us crazy.
What sort of pests are we dealing with?
We just bought this house, and it is
infected with just about everything.
We have termites in the
wood, cockroaches all over the
place, and last night I saw a
huge rat out in the backyard.
Well, there's nothing that we can handle.
I'll spray the floorboards and walls
to get rid of the cockroaches, but
the termites will be harder to get rid of.
We will have to cover the entire
house and fumigate it. Unfortunately,
that means you will have to find a
place to stay for the next three days.
No problem. Just get rid of the bugs.
All right, so now we've chosen three
key phrases for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Well, this first phrase comes from
the very beginning of today's dialogue.
The second person in the dialogue
says these bugs are driving us crazy.
So to drive someone crazy.
Okay, so if you're driving someone crazy,
it means that you're making them crazy.
All right, so it could be you're
making them angry, or you're
making them frustrated, but it
has nothing to do with cars, right?
Yeah, yeah, there's no driving involved.
So driving here means
making. You're making me crazy.
You're really making
me frustrated.
That's right. So in this case, the
animals, the bugs were driving them crazy.
They were so annoying that they
were just, they were very irritated.
So I could do something,
Marco, that will drive you crazy.
I could tap, tap, tap,
tap, tap, tap, tap, tap.
That's right. That's driving me crazy.
No, yes, yes.
So I'll stop.
So it doesn't drive you crazy anymore.
That's right. Okay.
So now, obviously, bugs are driving
them crazy, and she went on to explain
that it's because the house is
infested with just about everything.
Well, this is a great phrase because we
can say it in a lot of different contexts.
In this context, it means
there is not everything, every
single bug in the house,
but just about everything.
That means almost every bug
you can think of is in this house.
That's right. So it's kind
of a way of exaggerating
also because obviously,
well, they have cockroaches.
They have termites, but they're saying
we have a lot of different types of bugs.
We have just about
everything that you can imagine.
You can even say, this
restaurant has just about
every Chinese dish
you could ever think of.
That's not true. It doesn't have
every single one, but it has a lot.
That's right. Okay.
So that's the way that you
use just about everything.
And for our final phrase,
we use it a little bit earlier on.
Let's explain it a little bit.
When we're talking about
bugs, we want to get rid of bugs.
This is why we call the exterminator
to get rid of the cockroaches.
You might hear this phrase a lot
when you're watching movies about
gangsters or mobsters like the
Sopranos, the TV show, get rid of him.
So this is a phrase that means,
in this case, to kill something,
or to kill someone, to get
rid of it, to get rid of him.
To not have it anymore. Right.
So rid means to get away or to throw away.
But in this case, you're not just throwing
it away. You're killing these bugs.
That's right.
So we want to get rid of the bugs.
Now, obviously, as you
said, we can also throw
away, for example,
the shoes are too old.
I'm going to get rid of them.
Or hey, Marco, this milk smells funny.
Can you get rid of it?
Very good. So that's the way that you would
use that phrase to get rid of something.
So why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the very last time?
And we're back to talk a little bit more.
Chai, did you call for an exterminator?
Yes. Thank goodness you're here.
These bugs are driving us crazy.
What sort of pests are we dealing with?
We just bought this house and it is
infected with just about everything.
We have termites in the wood,
cockroaches all over the place.
And last night, I saw a
huge rat out in the backyard.
Well, there's nothing that we can't handle.
I'll spray the floorboards and
walls to get rid of the cockroaches,
but the termites will
be harder to get rid of.
We will have to cover the
entire house and fumigate it.
Unfortunately, that
means you will have to
find a place to stay
for the next three days.
No problem. Just get rid of the bugs.
So bugs, everyone loves bugs, right?
I don't know. I am actually okay with
termites or, for example, cockroaches.
They're a little bit weird, but
I actually really dislike spiders.
Really? So you're okay with
cockroaches, but spiders make you nervous.
Yeah, spiders are.
Well, the thing is, spiders
can actually hurt you.
That's right.
And cockroaches generally cannot.
They're gross. They're dirty.
But spiders, there are
very, very many kinds of
dangerous spiders out
there that are poisonous.
That's right. So for example,
termites, nothing's going to happen.
Cockroaches, they're nasty.
Not unless your house is weakened
by hundreds of millions of termites.
That's right.
But for example, I think other people
have snakes, sometimes that's pests,
because they live in areas
that have a lot of snakes or mice.
Because snakes are attracted by mice.
That's right.
So some people keep cats for that reason.
They want the cats,
especially on farms, that
cats catch the mice, or
to scare the snakes away.
But I don't really have a
problem with snakes or spiders,
but I do have a problem with scorpions.
Oh, scorpions.
If you live close to a desert or a very
dry area, scorpions, they really scare me.
I've seen on, I think, discovery channel
that in Australia, they're very common.
And so not only
scorpions, but also spiders.
So whenever you put your shoes on, you
have to check that there's nothing in it.
That's right.
Also, shower drains.
Where the water goes
down the hole in the shower.
Oftentimes you get
things like scorpions in
the desert areas that
come out of the drain.
Really?
Oh, wow.
That looks like something from
a horror movie or something.
Dude.
Yeah.
All of a sudden, you're in the shower,
and there's pests coming out of the drain.
That's nasty.
Terrifying.
A lot of different types
of scary bugs and pests.
But we would like to
know if you've ever had an
infestation in your home, or
what pests are you afraid of.
So let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
All right.
We'll see you guys next time.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]